<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[LunaTech design doc]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>LunaTech design doc</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 09:40:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 09:40:22 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[LunaTech project home]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>This is the index page for the project LunaTech and all of its technical and design documents regarding it.<br>
<a data-href="What is LunaTech?" href="lunatech/what-is-lunatech" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">What is LunaTech?</a><br>
<a data-href="Technology based elements" href="technology/technology-based-elements.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Technology based elements</a><br>
<a data-href="Story based elements" href="story/story-based-elements.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Story based elements</a>]]></description><link>lunatech/lunatech-project-home.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">LunaTech/LunaTech project home.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 21:33:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What is LunaTech?]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>LunaTech is a collection of inspirations from mods, and original ideas based on them, that is made into a somewhat comprehensive design document for a Minecraft Bedrock mod or if changed accordingly, basically any voxel sandbox survival game that allows modding.<br>So in a nutshell, LunaTech is a tech mod design document, that tries playing around the rules of Bedrock modding, while providing several ways of adapting to a technical problem.<br>This project was started after drinking way too much one evening (like a true lithuanian should) when i wrote this absolute piece of something, which explains an idea of a power system, more based on nuclear power that is harnessed from redstone itself.<br>]]></description><link>lunatech/what-is-lunatech/what-is-lunatech.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">LunaTech/What is LunaTech?.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 21:27:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[SoulTec]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>LunaTech industries is a leading exporter of exotic goods and minerals to all Human Colonies established outside the Andromeda galaxy, one of those exotic minerals were Soulstones, so called for their ability to bond the human soul to an electrically manipulated device, thus allowing basic immortality if the encoding is sufficient enough.<br>SoulTec devices are sophisticated card-like in appearance pieces of technology that lets a user to live practically indefinitely, apart from old age and some other cryptic stuff the LunaTech scientists haven't figured out yet.<br>These little devices let a user bound their soul to a matter fabricator that lets a user retain all items after death, including all of their experience.]]></description><link>story/soultec.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Story/SoulTec.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 21:49:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Story based elements]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>The story elements for this mod are a (from a developer side) a non required part, which just adds life to the world of LunaTech<br>Since the world LunaTech was based of a novel i wrote (more of a massive world-building guide that went way too long) the story elements represent some things happening in the story of the novel itself<br>You as the player are an explorer of a well known organisation called LunaTech industries (hence the name of the novel and the book, its the center of the entire ordeal) which is sent to explore planet Dromia, with a goal to uncover the secrets of it.<br>The index of the story elements are below<br>
<a data-href="SoulTec" href="story/soultec.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">SoulTec</a><br>
<a data-href="The Fauna of planet Dromia" href="story/the-fauna-of-planet-dromia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">The Fauna of planet Dromia</a>]]></description><link>story/story-based-elements.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Story/Story based elements.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 21:50:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Fauna of planet Dromia]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Planet Dromia is a very biologically diverse planet, that has biomes going from lush oceans and forests to lung rotting mushroom jungles and gigantic calcified tree structures beneath it all.<br>The animals -&gt;<br>
Just like in the Permian period of earth's development, the Dromia's fauna has massive insect like animals that have evolved into massive sized creatures, that are most of the time friendly or can even be tamed, although some more predator like creatures like to live in swarms making them extremely dangerous to the human player or any unfortunate animal that wanders into their hive or the area surrounding it<br>
the plants -&gt;<br>
some plants in planet Dromia have learned to sustain themselves with something that isnt sunlight and minerals in the soil, they have the ability to slowly move by having muscle like structures that allow them to travel long distances to hunt food or become a parasite for a massive tree for example.<br>the fungi biomes-&gt;<br>
The fungi fauna in Dromia has expanded into their own biomes due to high levels of radiation caused by natural redstone isotopes in the minerals surrounding them. These fungi jungles with massive tree like shroom structures and lush vegetation from an outside perspective can look like a paradise, but in reality without proper equipment your lungs would rot within minutes due to the extreme amounts of spores and other air based microorganisms. (taken a lot of inspiration from Nausica, a Ghibli studio movie)]]></description><link>story/the-fauna-of-planet-dromia.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Story/The Fauna of planet Dromia.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 09:33:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Technology based elements]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>This branch will explore all the technological aspects in LunaTech that i have planned, most ways that a technology work can be replicated in a few ways to work around the limitations of a game<br>
<a data-href="The problem with tech mods in a sandbox game" href="technology/the-problem-with-tech-mods-in-a-sandbox-game.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">The problem with tech mods in a sandbox game</a>]]></description><link>technology/technology-based-elements.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Technology/Technology based elements.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 09:38:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The problem with tech mods in a sandbox game]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 ]]></description><link>technology/the-problem-with-tech-mods-in-a-sandbox-game.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Technology/The problem with tech mods in a sandbox game.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 09:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>