<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[LunaTech design doc]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>LunaTech design doc</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 17:18:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 17:18:47 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[LunaTech project home]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>This is the index page for the project LunaTech and all of its technical and design documents regarding it.<br>
<a data-href="What is LunaTech?" href="lunatech/what-is-lunatech" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">What is LunaTech?</a><br>
<a data-href="Technology based elements" href="technology/technology-based-elements.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Technology based elements</a><br>
<a data-href="Story based elements" href="story/story-based-elements.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Story based elements</a>]]></description><link>lunatech/lunatech-project-home.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">LunaTech/LunaTech project home.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 21:33:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What is LunaTech?]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>LunaTech is a collection of inspirations from mods, and original ideas based on them, that is made into a somewhat comprehensive design document for a Minecraft Bedrock mod or if changed accordingly, basically any voxel sandbox survival game that allows modding.<br>So in a nutshell, LunaTech is a tech mod design document, that tries playing around the rules of Bedrock modding, while providing several ways of adapting to a technical problem.<br>This project was started after drinking way too much one evening (like a true lithuanian should) when i wrote this absolute piece of something, which explains an idea of a power system, more based on nuclear power that is harnessed from redstone itself.<br>]]></description><link>lunatech/what-is-lunatech/what-is-lunatech.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">LunaTech/What is LunaTech?.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 21:27:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[SoulTec]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>LunaTech industries is a leading exporter of exotic goods and minerals to all Human Colonies established outside the Andromeda galaxy, one of those exotic minerals were Soulstones, so called for their ability to bond the human soul to an electrically manipulated device, thus allowing basic immortality if the encoding is sufficient enough.<br>SoulTec devices are sophisticated card-like in appearance pieces of technology that lets a user to live practically indefinitely, apart from old age and some other cryptic stuff the LunaTech scientists haven't figured out yet.<br>These little devices let a user bound their soul to a matter fabricator that lets a user retain all items after death, including all of their experience.]]></description><link>story/soultec.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Story/SoulTec.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 21:49:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Story based elements]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>The story elements for this mod are a (from a developer side) a non required part, which just adds life to the world of LunaTech<br>Since the world LunaTech was based of a novel i wrote (more of a massive world-building guide that went way too long) the story elements represent some things happening in the story of the novel itself<br>You as the player are an explorer of a well known organisation called LunaTech industries (hence the name of the novel and the book, its the center of the entire ordeal) which is sent to explore planet Dromia, with a goal to uncover the secrets of it.<br>The index of the story elements are below<br>
<a data-href="SoulTec" href="story/soultec.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">SoulTec</a><br>
<a data-href="The Fauna of planet Dromia" href="story/the-fauna-of-planet-dromia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">The Fauna of planet Dromia</a>]]></description><link>story/story-based-elements.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Story/Story based elements.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 21:50:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Fauna of planet Dromia]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Planet Dromia is a very biologically diverse planet, that has biomes going from lush oceans and forests to lung rotting mushroom jungles and gigantic calcified tree structures beneath it all.<br>The animals -&gt;<br>
Just like in the Permian period of earth's development, the Dromia's fauna has massive insect like animals that have evolved into massive sized creatures, that are most of the time friendly or can even be tamed, although some more predator like creatures like to live in swarms making them extremely dangerous to the human player or any unfortunate animal that wanders into their hive or the area surrounding it<br>
the plants -&gt;<br>
some plants in planet Dromia have learned to sustain themselves with something that isnt sunlight and minerals in the soil, they have the ability to slowly move by having muscle like structures that allow them to travel long distances to hunt food or become a parasite for a massive tree for example.<br>the fungi biomes-&gt;<br>
The fungi fauna in Dromia has expanded into their own biomes due to high levels of radiation caused by natural redstone isotopes in the minerals surrounding them. These fungi jungles with massive tree like shroom structures and lush vegetation from an outside perspective can look like a paradise, but in reality without proper equipment your lungs would rot within minutes due to the extreme amounts of spores and other air based microorganisms. (taken a lot of inspiration from Nausica, a Ghibli studio movie)]]></description><link>story/the-fauna-of-planet-dromia.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Story/The Fauna of planet Dromia.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 09:33:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pressure management in LunaTech]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Since we now know that pressure is a critical aspect of this mod, how can players control it? The most basic pressure generators will be steam boilers and simple turbine-based systems. As players progress, they can start crafting more advanced pressure generators, such as hydraulic pressurizers. These use the force of weight and hydraulics to increase reactor pressure beyond the capabilities of earlier tiers. At the highest level, pressure management transitions from gases to extreme liquid pressurization, requiring advanced reactor designs capable of withstanding high pressure without bursting.<br>The core concept of pressure management in the game allows players to adjust pressure levels using manual or computer-controlled valves. This enables them to experiment with different pressure levels to find the optimal setting for maximizing reactor energy output.<br>To prevent players from finding a pressure "sweet spot" early on and never adjusting it, external factors will be introduced. These include varying outside pressure based on environmental conditions. For example, in rainy or stormy weather, most pressurizers would suffer a 10% efficiency debuff due to lower atmospheric pressure. Conversely, living in deserts, where atmospheric pressure is more stable due to the lack of weather, could help mitigate this issue.]]></description><link>technology/pressure-management-in-lunatech.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Technology/Pressure management in LunaTech.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 10:57:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Redstone isotopes 2 Electric boogaloo]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>As mentioned in <a data-href="Redstone Isotope based nuclear power.pdf" href="lunatech/redstone-isotope-based-nuclear-power.pdf" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Redstone Isotope based nuclear power.pdf</a> redstone in the universe is a powerful material that has the properties of lithium and uranium at the same time, thus making this material suitable for nuclear reactors or even extremely basic power generation<br>The main thing with redstone isotopes is that pressure improves it's ability to generate energy, by compromising the longevity of the fuel itself<br>That means that a starter RTG made by a player in their first days of the game can be slowly upgraded into a pressurised and optimised RTG that can power even the most power hungry machines, thus leaving the player a reason to not throw out the old machines they have made.<br>How pressure affects the power output depends on the pressure and the isotope used<br>
here is an example of a graph to explain how an isotope can react to pressure<br>
First class isotopes react to pressure with a formula of sqrt(x*\100)<br>
<img alt="desmos-graph(2).png" src="technology/desmos-graph(2).png"><br>
X is pressure, Y is extra power generated<br>
the RED line is for extra power generation on top of the default machine output<br>
the PURPLE line shows the heat units generated and the limit of when the isotope reaches its heat limit and combusts catastrophically and destroys the machine violently<br>
(aka the maximum power output and heat capacity of a class 1 isotope is 2000 extra energy units and 1000 heat units)]]></description><link>technology/redstone-isotopes-2-electric-boogaloo.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Technology/Redstone isotopes 2 Electric boogaloo.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 10:44:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="technology/desmos-graph(2).png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;technology/desmos-graph(2).png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Technology based elements]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>This branch will explore all the technological aspects in LunaTech that i have planned, most ways that a technology work can be replicated in a few ways to work around the limitations of a game<br>
<a data-href="The problem with tech mods in a sandbox game" href="technology/the-problem-with-tech-mods-in-a-sandbox-game.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">The problem with tech mods in a sandbox game</a><br>
<a data-href="Redstone isotopes 2 Electric boogaloo" href="technology/redstone-isotopes-2-electric-boogaloo.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Redstone isotopes 2 Electric boogaloo</a><br>
<a data-href="Pressure management in LunaTech" href="technology/pressure-management-in-lunatech.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Pressure management in LunaTech</a>]]></description><link>technology/technology-based-elements.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Technology/Technology based elements.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 10:57:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The problem with tech mods in a sandbox game]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Tech mods in sandbox games often lack clear objectives, which can leave players feeling confused or misguided, ultimately leading to frustration or boredom. To address this, some mods or modpacks incorporate quests or story elements to guide players through the technological stages naturally.<br>My solution to this issue draws inspiration from the game RimWorld. In RimWorld, all technological progress is tied to a simple goal: escaping the planet you crash-landed on. To achieve this, players must survive and advance through various technological stages via research or exploration, providing a clear motivation to progress. While the game offers multiple endings, most players prefer the straightforward goal of escape rather than pursuing more complex objectives like world domination, which would take an excessive amount of time.<br>The RimAtomics mod in RimWorld offers a unique research system that includes risks, failures, and other factors, making the research process more engaging than simply waiting for it to complete. Research should require active player involvement, such as building a nuclear research station before constructing a nuclear reactor, discovering new types of synthesis, or developing more powerful isotopes. Additionally, the research system can seamlessly integrate with the mod's story, offering natural progression without forcing the player to follow a specific narrative. For instance, after starting research on the radio branch, a player might begin receiving transmissions or SOS signals, or when exploring fusion technology using soulstones as fuel, they might experience strange visions or hear voices guiding them to a specific location.<br>In conclusion, this research system keeps players engaged without forcing them into the story if they prefer to explore at their own pace.]]></description><link>technology/the-problem-with-tech-mods-in-a-sandbox-game.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Technology/The problem with tech mods in a sandbox game.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 10:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>